{
    "id": "c7b158bd258045f0b65150f27860b818",
    "title": "Nouns And Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The horse and carriage ………………….. waiting at the door.",
            "description": "The verb is singular when two or more nouns suggest one idea to the mind or refer to the same person or thing.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2ea551abd18d4db5af2010b5daf7dc14"
        },
        {
            "question": "No nook or corner ……………………. left unexplored.",
            "description": "Two or more singular subjects connected by or require a singular verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "cbbcfaabdc3b48bf990d167176dcf1d0"
        },
        {
            "question": "The quality of the apples ………………………… not very good.",
            "description": "Here the proper subject is the singular expression ‘quality’ and hence the verb should be singular.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3fc05f8e9add43688e55323367bf8c6c"
        },
        {
            "question": "His knowledge of Indian languages ……………………….. commendable.",
            "description": "Here the proper subject is the singular expression ‘knowledge’ and hence the verb should be singular.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d6eeca308e804284be957381878278d0"
        },
        {
            "question": "Excessive consumption of beverages such as tea and coffee …………………….adverse effects on health.",
            "description": "Here the proper subject is the singular expression ‘consumption’ and hence the verb should be singular.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b037d8a7d9ef4492a7910861eaad29ea"
        },
        {
            "question": "The rise and the fall of the tide ……………………… due to the influence of the moon.",
            "description": "The verb is singular when two or more nouns suggest one idea to the mind or refer to the same person or thing.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d1e048ae078349b9a6b1418d02f97b4b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Please allow John and ………………………. to go to the movies.",
            "description": "Here the noun John and the pronoun me are the objects of the verb allow. Pronouns used as objects should be in their object form.",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "me",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bb637f1e77434c42855af8b6c801208d"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is as good a player as ……………………",
            "description": "Either I am or me is possible here. The subject pronoun is not normally used after ‘as’ without a following verb.",
            "answers": [
                "me",
                "I",
                "I am"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "af107eb6a64a4d6bbce9bf229959d343"
        },
        {
            "question": "All passengers must buy …………………… tickets.",
            "description": "A pronoun must agree with its antecedent in number, gender and person.",
            "answers": [
                "their",
                "our",
                "his",
                "her"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "33690ddeb2844c17aa2759f156f0ba15"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every man must bear ………………….. own burden.",
            "description": "\r\nA pronoun must agree with its antecedent in number, gender and person.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "his",
                "their",
                "our"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0c234e4b01d8406bad53d642ae9f833e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Each girl gave ……………………… own version of the story.",
            "description": "A pronoun must agree with its antecedent in number, gender and person.",
            "answers": [
                "their",
                "her",
                "our"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "31b70a78aeb744f8aba90ba128298176"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not one of those who believe everything ……………………. hear.",
            "description": "Here the pronoun 'they' refers back to 'those'. ",
            "answers": [
                "I",
                "you",
                "they"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5bdf7a6bfa0f4be6b68866e4274dc865"
        }
    ]
}